<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://alonkellner.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://alonkellner.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2024-07-31T20:46:26+00:00</updated><id>https://alonkellner.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">WaloViz is Out!</title><link href="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/waloviz-out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WaloViz is Out!"/><published>2024-07-31T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-31T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/waloviz-out</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/waloviz-out/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://waloviz.com">:globe_with_meridians: WaloViz Website :globe_with_meridians:</a>, <a href="https://github.com/AlonKellner/waloviz/">:star: GitHub Repo :star:</a>, <a href="https://colab.research.google.com/drive/1euQCxaNlTg0pGvXz6d7RSoDhM3B1k7dy">:arrow_forward: Google Colab Demo :arrow_forward:</a>, <a href="../../../projects/open-source_2024-07-25_waloviz">:bust_in_silhouette: Portfolio Project Page :bust_in_silhouette:</a></p> <p><br/></p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/waloviz-logo-horizontal-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/waloviz-logo-horizontal-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/waloviz-logo-horizontal-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/waloviz-logo-horizontal.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="The WaloViz logo" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Take a look at the <a href="https://waloviz.com">official WaloViz website!</a> </div> <h2 id="audio--jupyter--tired_face">Audio + Jupyter == :tired_face:</h2> <p>On every single audio research project I got into I faced the same problem again and again - working with audio in Jupyter notebooks is too difficult!</p> <p>Specifically, inspecting an audio snippet in depth is a surprisingly difficult task, it requires both listening and viewing something called a spectrogram (see my explanation about <a href="../../../projects/open-source_2024-07-25_waloviz/#whats-a-spectrogram">What’s a Spectrogram?</a>).<br/> That is precisely what I made WaloViz for, working with audio in Jupyter notebooks, like so:</p> <div class="jupyter-notebook" style="position: relative; width: 100%; margin: 0 auto;"> <div class="jupyter-notebook-iframe-container"> <iframe src="/assets/jupyter/waloviz/tldr.ipynb.html" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; border-style: none;" width="100%" height="100%" onload="this.parentElement.style.paddingBottom = (this.contentWindow.document.documentElement.scrollHeight + 10) + 'px'"></iframe> </div> </div> <p>Try clicking the spectrogram above, it will start playing :)<br/> To learn more about how to use WaloViz go to the <a href="https://waloviz.com">WaloViz Documentation Website!</a></p> <h2 id="my-first-open-source-project">My First Open-Source Project!</h2> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/waloviz-github-top-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/waloviz-github-top-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/waloviz-github-top-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/waloviz-github-top.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Our GitHub Repo!" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> If you want to contribute, come to our <a href="https://github.com/AlonKellner/waloviz/">GitHub Repo!</a> Take a look around and say hi, we're friendly :) </div> <p>WaloViz is the first open-source project that I own, I am really excited to get to build an open-source community.<br/> If you like it, consider giving us a :star2: on our <a href="https://github.com/AlonKellner/waloviz/">GitHub Repo</a>!</p> <p>If you want to contribute - <strong>WaloViz is a Beginner Friendly project!</strong><br/> We welcome anyone to contribute, no matter your experience level.<br/> Here are three things that make WaloViz great for beginners:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Our codebase is SMALL</strong> - there is not much to learn to start working</li> <li><strong>Everything is DOCUMENTED</strong> - our standard is to document inline each and every single function, method or class</li> <li><strong>Standards are AUTOMATED</strong> - what are our code standards? Automated testing, formatting, linting and type-checking will help you with that :)</li> </ol> <p>Want to give it a go? Start by reading our <a href="https://github.com/AlonKellner/waloviz/">README</a> and then read our <a href="https://github.com/AlonKellner/waloviz/blob/main/CONTRIBUTING.md">Contributing Guide</a>, you can do it!</p> <p>WaloViz is in early-alpha, but we plan to go Beta in a month, and later this year - an official <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1.0</code> version!</p> <p>That’s it for WaloViz for now, I will publish updates when the Beta arrives next month, and hopefully more open-source projects are coming soon, so stay tuned :wink:</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="professional"/><category term="software"/><category term="research"/><category term="open-source"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My newest open-source project, WaloViz]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deeper into the Portfolio</title><link href="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-deeper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deeper into the Portfolio"/><published>2024-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-30T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-deeper</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-deeper/"><![CDATA[<div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/plant-roots-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/plant-roots-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/plant-roots-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/plant-roots.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Under the surface" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Close Up Photo of a Person Holding Plant and a Pot, from <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/close-up-photo-of-a-person-holding-plant-and-a-pot-4751968/">Pexels</a> </div> <p>This post is a deep dive into some of the concepts I introduced in the first post: <a href="../portfolio-start">My Portfolio Year Starts</a>.<br/> Make sure to read it before you start reading this one :)</p> <h2 id="a-philosophy-of-personal-growth">A Philosophy of Personal Growth</h2> <p>My goal in life is to be happy, I think that’s a fair starting point.</p> <p>I know that my happiness comes from things in my life, these things are not very strict or well defined, but they do follow certain patterns, and I believe I recognized some of these patterns in my own life.</p> <p>One of those patterns I call “People”, people around me in my life make me happy. Simple.<br/> Another pattern I call “Creation”, making something that was conceived by my own mind into a reality makes me happy. Not simple, but understandable.</p> <p>To be happy all I need to do is experience these patterns regularly - now <strong>that’s</strong> a Challenge.</p> <p>Four things can aid me in overcoming this Challenge:</p> <ol> <li><strong>Environment</strong> - outside influence which I do not have direct control over, but I can get close to or away from if I want to. For example my workplace.</li> <li><strong>Systems</strong> - self-constructed outside influence which I have full control over. For example a schedule management app.</li> <li><strong>Tools</strong> - outside aids to my abilities. For example a laptop.</li> <li><strong>Self</strong> - internal strength and capabilities. For example perseverance.</li> </ol> <p>There is an old saying by Abraham Lincoln:</p> <blockquote> <p>Give me six hours to chop down a tree and I will spend the first four sharpening the axe.</p> </blockquote> <p>In that metaphor, if the tree is my Challenge, the forest is my Environment, a sharpening procedure is a System, the axe is a Tool, and finally my hands and muscles are my Self.</p> <p>If I were to cut a tree in six hours, I better have already trained my body to be strong enough to swing the axe, if I didn’t, even 12 hours of sharpening won’t get me anywhere.</p> <p>So it’s like a diamond shaped tower, in the base there is the Self, supported by it are Tools and Systems and on the very top is the Environment.<br/> The higher up the tower - the easier to build.</p> <p>By that logic the most difficult thing to build is the Self. Therefore - personal growth is the first, longest and most difficult step in overcoming the Happiness Challenge.</p> <p>My Portfolio Year is a part of a life long journey to strengthen my Self, specifically focused on my “Creation” happiness pattern.</p> <p>In this year I will strengthen my Self “Planning” muscle, this muscle is used for many things:</p> <ol> <li>Consolidate internal goals with external goals</li> <li>Making calculated choices</li> <li>Self management</li> <li>Parallelism</li> <li>Life balance</li> </ol> <p>and more.</p> <p>The “Planning” muscle is crucial to “Creation”, it’s my way of making that connection between my mind and reality, without this muscle I might work hard all day long and achieve nothing, or maybe something entirely different than what I originally conceived.</p> <p>Phew! That got deep indeed.<br/> But actually, that’s just an elaborate way to say something very simple:<br/> <strong>This year I will become better at “Getting Shit Done”.</strong></p> <h2 id="the-professionals-obligation-of-proof">The Professional’s Obligation of Proof</h2> <p>As established when I introduced <a href="#a-philosophy-of-personal-growth">A Philosophy of Personal Growth</a>, my main reason for My Portfolio Year is personal growth to achieve happiness.<br/> The lesser reason I want a portfolio is that I believe in “The Professional’s Obligation of Proof”.</p> <p>That’s a mouthful, but what is it?<br/> Simply put, it’s an answer for the question “Why should I trust or respect you?”<br/> It’s a question we face a lot, in job interviews, auditions, negotiations, commerce, residence, relationships, university, social media, in every single aspect of our lives we are implicitly asked this question.</p> <p>There are a few good answers to that question:</p> <ol> <li>Someone else says so (an institution, associates, a community)</li> <li>Test me (interview questions, homework, a formal test)</li> <li>Look me up (social media, online reputation)</li> <li>Here’s a proof (portfolio, verifiable examples, valuable examples)</li> </ol> <p>Each of these have good and bad examples which I will not get into in this post, but their all important in their own ways.<br/> So why emphasize the proof?</p> <p>Well, I believe that a true Professional is obligated to supply all four when asked to, but for some reason in the Technological and Academical industries there is an obvious lack of proof, it exists but its weight is so much smaller than the other 3 that many don’t bother with it.</p> <p>So, yes - high quality proof is as important as any other high quality answer, and a good portfolio can be an amazing proof.</p> <h2 id="my-success-criteria">My Success Criteria</h2> <p>I outlined 3 criteria for successful portfolio projects:</p> <ol> <li>It <strong>demonstrates a skill</strong> of mine</li> <li>It was a <strong>collaboration</strong></li> <li>It received <strong>community recognition</strong></li> </ol> <p>Why these three?<br/> Well, the first one is obvious, the second and third are not so.</p> <h4 id="why-must-i-collaborate">Why must I Collaborate?</h4> <p>This is about making the most out of this year, as explained in the <a href="#a-philosophy-of-personal-growth">A Philosophy of Personal Growth</a> section, this year focuses on my “Planning” muscle, which is all about making the connection between my mind and reality.</p> <p>It is about making myself front problems which are not internal.<br/> It’s not about determination, perseverance or dedication which are purely internal traits which are fully dependent on me alone.<br/> It’s about estimation, agility, calculation, responsiveness and yes - also collaboration.</p> <p>Other people are a part of reality, but it’s more than that, working with people is a strength on its own, we all know that.</p> <p>So yeah, Collaboration is a must.</p> <h4 id="why-must-it-be-recognized-by-a-community">Why must it be Recognized by a Community?</h4> <p>Well, it’s just the simplest way to show value.</p> <p>My portfolio needs prove my skills, and I claim that my skills are valuable, proving that they are valuable is as easy as showing enough people recognizing it.</p> <p>It could be stars on GitHub, or retweets on X, or even downloads from PyPi and obviously citations on arxiv.</p> <p>This means that whatever I do this year - at least half of it will be about the community, either building it, interacting with it, or just being a part of it.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="ideas"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Deeper thoughts about the portfolio year and its meaning to me]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Portfolio Year Starts</title><link href="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Portfolio Year Starts"/><published>2024-07-29T13:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-29T13:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://alonkellner.com/blog/2024/portfolio-start/"><![CDATA[<div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/plant-a-seed-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/plant-a-seed-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/plant-a-seed-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/plant-a-seed.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="The start of something new" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> A CIMMYT researcher plants wheat seed, from <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/cimmyt/8208414846">flickr</a> </div> <p>I am growing as a person.<br/> We all are, all of the time actually, but sometimes we put ourselves in a place where we can grow faster.<br/> That is why I’m doing this, dedicating a whole year of my life to create a portfolio.</p> <p>Many are surprised at the concept, why skip a year in your life for projects and research?<br/> My portfolio year is similar to taking a seminar or working on a thesis, it’s not a waste - it’s an investment.</p> <p>The most probable profit is personal growth, but if opportunities will come through doing this publicly - that will be a great bonus :)</p> <p>I wrote more thoughts about growth in another post: <a href="../portfolio-deeper#a-philosophy-of-personal-growth">Deeper into the Portfolio</a>.</p> <h2 id="define-portfolio">Define “Portfolio”</h2> <p>Well, you’re looking at it! This website is my portfolio, or at least the beginning of it.</p> <p>Most people might know portfolios as a concept from the entertainment or the arts and crafts industries, when you go to an interview or an audition your portfolio comes along your resume, if a resume is a description of your skills - a portfolio is a <strong>proof</strong> of them.</p> <p>I wrote more about the importance of proof in another post: <a href="../portfolio-deeper#the-professionals-obligation-of-proof">Deeper into the Portfolio</a>.</p> <p>This portfolio is very similar, but I am not a painter that can show her painting, I am an Engineer and a Researcher, so my portfolio will consist of Engineering Projects and Research Papers.</p> <p>I decided to dedicate at least on whole year to working on a portfolio, I call it My Portfolio Year.<br/> My portfolio year starts now - the 01st of August, 2024 - and ends in exactly one year from now - the 01st of August, 2025.</p> <p>I have set myself a goal to achieve until the end of this year:</p> <blockquote> <p>GOAL: <strong>Between 5 and 10 Successful Projects and Papers</strong> .</p> </blockquote> <p>Where “Successful” means 3 things:</p> <ol> <li>It <strong>demonstrates a skill</strong> of mine</li> <li>It was a <strong>collaboration</strong></li> <li>It received <strong>community recognition</strong></li> </ol> <p>I elaborate about these criteria in another post: <a href="../portfolio-deeper#my-success-criteria">Deeper into the Portfolio</a>.</p> <h2 id="so-whats-the-plan">So, What’s the Plan?</h2> <p>In the next six months I want to finish the majority of the technical work of 5 projects, and dedicate the last six months to refinement and publication of those 5.<br/> If I’ll have any spare time - I will try to work on some backup projects, in case one of those 5 fails to meet my success criteria.</p> <p>I cannot reveal all of the details of the 5 projects I have planned just yet, but here is a short description of each one of them:</p> <ol> <li><a href="https://waloviz.com"><strong>WaloViz</strong></a> - An open-source python package of a Jupyter notebook audio player with a spectrogram built-in. <strong>WaloViz is out NOW!</strong> Read <a href="../waloviz-out">my blog post about it</a> :)</li> <li><strong>CHFSto</strong> - Not live yet. An open-source python package that will allow you to use your favorite libraries (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">os</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pathlib</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">shutil</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">requests</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pandas</code> and more) with any url scheme (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">file</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">http</code>\<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">https</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">s3</code> and more). More updates soon.</li> <li><strong>Number Theory paper</strong> - I proved some nice properties about sets of reciprocal numbers that add up to whole numbers, I will formalize them and publish them in a paper. More details soon.</li> <li><strong>Botanical Dataset</strong> - A long story led me to start building an automated pipeline for creating a center aligned images dataset, of three main categories: Eggs, Butterflies and Molluscs.</li> <li><strong>E2E Multi-Speaker Identification with Weak labels</strong> - This is a concept which was part of a project I worked on, it proved to be promising, I plan to reproduce the concept on multiple models and datasets to evaluate the effectiveness of the method.</li> </ol> <p>These are the projects which I feel confident about, other projects which I plan to try are more risky and less mature, but stay tuned and I might share my thoughts about them along the way :)</p> <p>If any of these interest you, contact me! It might be an opportunity for a wonderful collaboration.<br/> Either send me an email or DM me at any of my social platforms.</p> <h2 id="this-is-it">This is it.</h2> <p>Now - My Portfolio Year starts.<br/> My success depends on me alone, and still - wish me luck :)</p> <p>I will post regular updates in this blog, as well as major updates through social media, make sure to follow me if you’re interested.</p> <p>If you have any thoughts you would like to share with me - please do! You can leave a comment below, email me or DM me at any of my social platforms, it would be my pleasure to talk!</p> <p>Thank you for starting this journey with me :)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><category term="ideas"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Portfolio year, dedicated to achieving successful projects and publications]]></summary></entry></feed>